### **ERIN SAWYER**

(864) 414-7960 ♦ ensawyer@novanthealth.org

# **Radiology Instructional Designer**

Outgoing, highly motivated Training Coordinator and Instructional Designer with extensive experience teaching and training in technical and medical environments within a variety of industries. Proven track record of conceptualizing and developing age-appropriate curriculum, creating training documentation and manuals, and managing time and projects for effective instruction. Strong verbal and written communicator, and able to create individual training plans that meet the needs of all participants.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Technical Training • Wiki Development • Curriculum Development • Manual Creation
Instructional Design • Teaching • Collaboration • Leadership • Verbal & Written Communication
Time Management • Workflow Optimization • Customer Service • Research & Analysis
Epic • Adobe Captivate • E-Learning Curriculum • Microsoft 2010 Master Certified

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### Novant Health, Charlotte, NC

**Acting Training Coordinator/ Central Scheduler II / Insurance Verification,** January 2016-Present

- Hired as Central Scheduler II/ Insurance Verification Specialist but due to education background was tasked with implementing brand new Department-wide training program
- Training program has resulted in a significant increase in the quality, productivity, and over all satisfaction and retention of the new hires in both markets.
- Created new hire survey to find out the strengths and weaknesses of the current new hire training program.
- Identified current and potential trainers. Sent them learning surveys to find out their learning styles, strengths and weaknesses, and how much they know about current programs and processes.
- Developed curriculum to teach new hires in a classroom setting including interactive games and tests
- Designed interactive curriculum with Adobe Captivate to use in the LMS system.
- Developed teaching modules and training checklists for the trainers.
- Developed a continuing education class on scheduling errors based off of the most common errors.
   The error class engaged the participants and cultivated teamwork to find out how the errors impact the patient and what can be done to avoid them in the future.
- Developed a continuing education class on insurance topics. Created an interactive PowerPoint that would appeal to visual and auditory learners. Created several mnemonic devices to help the schedulers remember information easily. For review after the PowerPoint, schedulers played Jeopardy in groups to encourage teamwork and apply several levels of the Bloom's Taxonomy of Learning to reinforce concepts.
- Created and led webinars to teach and guide schedulers with new procedures and implementations.
- Sent out email updates to the supervisors to keep them informed on where the trainee is and what the game plan is for the upcoming weeks.
- Leading and coaching the trainers through the development of a Customer Service class.
- Leading monthly meetings with the trainers in both markets and discussed current issues and future goals and projects.
- Verified insurance, benefits and authorizations in both Davinci and Epic.
- Obtained authorization for many different insurance carriers.
- Called patients to reschedule when there is no active authorization on file.
- Answers calls related to insurance verification and authorization from patients and center employees.
- Cross trained in NMG scheduling.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Designed and created a radiology wiki for the schedulers in both markets to use. The wiki utilizes the most up-to-date information that all schedulers will have access to.
- Developed a new hire training program that includes classroom training which allows new hires to get trained quicker and be more confident and competent.

#### MEDQUEST, Alpharetta, GA

### Patient Account Services Representative, 2013-2016

- Coordinated with the accounts receivable and posting departments, imaging centers, collection agencies, and outside vendors to assist patients in resolving billing inquiries and issues.
- Answered calls related to billing, which includes questions about patient statements, collecting payments, and setting up payment plans.
- Completed reports regarding accounts being sent to collections.
- Reviewed accounts for collections and sends them if they meet certain criteria.
- Reported patient collection payments to the appropriate collection agency.
- Meet collection goals every month and exceeded the goal from February 2014 July 2015.
- Exceeded Customer Service monitored calls with a score of 98% out of 100% for 2014, and 98.3% for 2015.
- Exceeded the goal for daily accounts worked with an average of 159.55 daily accounts worked in 2014 and 168.92 in 2015. The goal is 135 accounts.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Developed and formatted a training notebook for new hires.
- Created Quick Reference Guides for new processes and procudures.
- Lead and taught classes on new procedures and Microsoft applications.
- Trained new hires for both the phone and reports teams.

#### INTELLITEACH, Atlanta, GA

### **Technical Trainer**, 2012-2013

- Delivered training for new hires that covered company policy, law firm structure, ticketing systems, customer service, and technical training.
- Designed and developed curriculum and quick reference guides for various law firm applications.
- Conceptualized and created online learning curriculums in TrainCaster Learning Management System (LMS).
- Coordinated and executed interactive activities, training surveys, and assessments for use with the new hire class and ongoing learning events.
- Proctored Microsoft Office certification tests.
- Contributed to training requirements and gatherings with various clients.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Achieved Microsoft 2010 Master Certification within a six-month time period.
- Gathered, designed, and developed materials for a "Trainer's Toolkit" within 30 days of hire.
- Heavily contributed to the redesign of the LMS structure and curriculum.

### TIME WARNER CABLE (TWC), Charlotte, NC

## **Signature Home Personal Solution Advisor,** 2011-2012

- Provided Tier 1, 2, and 3 support for cable modems, wired and wireless networking, audio/video, phone, operating system configuration, mobile device applications, and basic email problems.
- Utilized a thorough knowledge of billing system functions, order entry processes, TWC marketing strategies and pricing structure, TWC products and services, and troubleshooting of all products and services.
- Coordinated with accounting, finance, collections, engineering, and technical operations departments for the purpose of assisting clients in resolving inquires or issues.
- Provided quality service to customers via phone in account activation, maintenance, billing, problem solving, modification, enhancement and, when required, de-activation.

#### **Kev Accomplishments:**

• Provided customers with additional support resources and helped them learn basic troubleshooting techniques, which allowed them to self-help many common end-user issues.

 Assisted customers in finding optimal product solutions in accordance with TWC sales guidelines, simultaneously increasing customer value and deriving additional company revenue streams.

### JL MANN ACADEMY, Greenville, SC

### Spanish I & II Teacher, 2009-2011

- Created meaningful lesson plans and curriculum that taught to all learning styles, such as spatial, auditory, linguistic, visual, kinesthetic, interpersonal and intrapersonal.
- Maintained an active classroom management plan.
- Served as an active member on the transitions committee, which formed programs to help students succeed in high school, particularly those coming in from the middle school.
- Co-sponsored the Spanish Culture Club, introducing students to other Hispanic countries and cultures and promoting volunteer work in the community.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Demonstrated natural ability to teach to a variety of personalities, effectively recognizing the best methods to share knowledge with each individual.
- Went above and beyond assigned duties as a teacher by actively participating in the mentor program, which mentored at-risk students in danger of dropping out, as well as the homebound program, which tutored students who missed school due to an illness and enabled them to remain on-schedule for the school year.

### WACCAMAW HIGH SCHOOL, Pawleys Island, SC

### Spanish I, II, III, IV International Baccalaureate Teacher, 2007-2009

- Conceptualized, developed, and executed lesson plans and curriculum, catering to individual learning styles and language levels.
- As an International Baccalaureate (IB)-trained teacher, taught and prepared students to take the IB test in Spanish by teaching them with an international perspective and with a focus on critically thinking in the Spanish language.
- Instructed and supervised the color guard squad by going to practices and helping the guard with their routine.

#### **Kev Accomplishments:**

- Promoted volunteer work as a co-sponsor of the Spanish club, including building a Habitat for Humanity house and collecting goods for the Hispanic community.
- Helped form the Invisible Children Club.

# Woodruff High & Middle School, Woodruff, SC

### Spanish I & Exploratory Spanish, 2006 - 2007

- Created meaningful lesson plans and curriculum that taught to all learning styles, such as spatial, auditory, linguistic, visual, kinesthetic, interpersonal and intrapersonal.
- Maintained an active classroom management plan.
- Served as an active leader of the Spanish Culture Club.

### Dorman High School, Roebuck, SC

#### Spanish I, 2006

- Created meaningful lesson plans and curriculum that taught to all learning styles, such as spatial, auditory, linguistic, visual, kinesthetic, interpersonal and intrapersonal.
- Maintained an active classroom management plan.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Art, Secondary Education/Spanish, University of South Carolina Upstate, Spartanburg,
   SC
  - Foreign Language Honors Society
  - President's List
  - Dean's List